Poinsettias for Christmas is a romance, tv movie
film directed by Christie Will Wolf.
It’s just weeks before Christmas when Ellie gets a call to return home
to help her father on the family’s poinsettia farm.
The family business is on the line to deliver tens of
thousands of plants for the town’s annual parade.
The problem is — the poinsettias have yet to turn red!
As Ellie searches for the solution, she is reminded of where her heart truly lies
as she falls in love with both her roots and a local botanist.
Ellie Palmer, played by Bethany Joy Lenz.
Katherine Palmer, played by Sharon Lawrence.
Greg Palmer, played by John Schneider.
Patty Mason, played by Lauren London.
Shawn Dalton, played by Marcus Rosner.
Grace Palmer, played by Rhonda Dent.
The poinsettia (; Euphorbia pulcherrima) is a commercially important
flowering plant species of the diverse spurge family Euphorbiaceae.
Indigenous to Mexico and Central America, the poinsettia
was first described by Europeans in 1834.
It is particularly well known for its red and green foliage and
is widely used in Christmas floral displays.
It derives its common English name from Joel Roberts Poinsett, the first United States minister to Mexico, who is credited with introducing the plant to the US in the 1820s;
however, there have been recent efforts to rename the flower to its Nahuatl name, "cuetlaxōchitl", due to Poinsett's involvement in slavery and the Trail of Tears.
Poinsettias are shrubs or small trees, with
heights of 0.6 to 4 m (2.0 to 13.1 ft).
Though often stated to be highly toxic, the poinsettia
is not dangerous to pets or children.
Exposure to the plant, even consumption, most often results in no
effect, though it can cause nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea.
Wild poinsettias occur from Mexico to southern Guatemala,
growing on mid-elevation, Pacific-facing slopes.
One population in the Mexican state of Guerrero is much further inland, however,
and is thought to be the ancestor of most cultivated populations.
Wild poinsettia populations are highly fragmented, as their habitat
is experiencing largely unregulated deforestation.
They were cultivated by the Aztecs for use in traditional medicine.
They became associated with the Christmas holiday
and are popular seasonal decorations.
Every year in the United States, approximately 70 million poinsettias of
many cultivated varieties are sold in a six-week period.
Many of these poinsettias are grown by Paul Ecke Ranch, which serves
half the worldwide market and 70 percent of the US market.
The tone is emotional.